William N. Fenton Papers 1933-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.20
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Works by others, 1848-1994; 10 boxes; 4.5 linear feet
  - "Sixteenth Century Depopulation: A View from the Mohawk Valley"--Ms., Jan. 1988; Snow, Dean R. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Iroquois False Faces"--Ms., 1961; Spittal, William Guy (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Whose History Will Be Taught, and What is History Anyway?", [7 Mar. 1990]; Starna, William A. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Anthropologists as Expert Witnesses for Indians: Claims and Peyote Cases"--Ms., 1970; Stewart, Omer C. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Taos Functionalism"--Ms., 1981; Stewart, Omer C. (Box Series IV-9)
  - History Research: a Manual of Library Sources, 1977; Stoffle, Carla and Simon Karter (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Patagonian Giants and Baroness Hyde De Neuville's Iroquois Drawings"--Ms., 1980; Sturtevant, William C. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Seneca Masks"--Ms., 1980; Sturtevant, William C. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "The Cornplanter Cemetery: a Demography Appraisal"--Ms., [1964]; Sublett, Audrey J. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Protective American Indian Legislation: Retrospection and Prospects"--Address, [1982]; Symes, Martha I. (Box Series IV-9)
    Given at Amer. Anthropological Assoc. Mtg., Dec. 1982
  - "The Hale-Morgan Correspondence"--Ms., [198-]; Tooker, Elisabeth. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Lewis H. Morgan and His Contemporaries", [1985]; Tooker, Elisabeth. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Lewis H. Morgan's Study of Iroquois Calendric Ceremonies"--Ms., [1972]; Tooker, Elisabeth. (Box Series IV-9)
  - [Mid-Winter Manuscript], [1969]; Tooker, Elisabeth. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "A Note on George Washington's Indian Name"--Ms., [1989]; Tooker, Elisabeth. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "On the Development of the Handsome Lake Religion", [1986]; Tooker, Elisabeth. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Some Reflections on Cherokee-Iroquois Culture History"--Ms., [1978]; Tooker, Elisabeth. (Box Series IV-9)
  - Cartier's Hochelaga and the Dawson Site, [Jun. 1973]; Trigger, Bruce G. (Box Series IV-9)
    -See Ser.IV, Pendergast, James F. [Same Title]
  - "Champlain Judged by His Indian Policy: a Different View of Early Canadian History"--Ms., [1967]; Trigger, Bruce G. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Iroquois Country, 1794"--Ms. from Little Brother of War, Vennum, Thomas, Jr. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "The Shawnee Eagle Dance"--Ms., Erminie Wheeler-Voegelin, 1903-1988 (Box Series IV-9)
    -See Ser.III, [Same title]
  - "American Indian Medicine and Its Influence on White Medicine and Pharmacology"--Abstract, 1966; Vogel, Virgil J. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Chapter on Mythology to be Included in a Book on the Iroquoian Tobacco Complex"--Ms., Jun. 1990; von Gernet, Alexander D. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "'Gens de Petun': A Case Study in Exegesis and the Deconstruction of Images in Ethnohistory"--Ms., Dec. 1989; von Gernet, Alexander D. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Some Observations on the Hallucinogenic Origins of the Iroquoian Pipe/Tobacco/Smoking Complex"--Ms., Jun. 1989; von Gernet, Alexander D. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "The Transculturation of the Amerindian Pipe/Tobacco/Smoking Complex and Its Impact on the Intellectual Boundaries between 'Savagery' and 'Civilization', 1535-1935"--Abstract, Sep. 1988; von Gernet, Alexander D. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "The Institutionalization of Cathartic and Control Strategies in Iroquois Religious Psychotherapy"--Ms., [1957]; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923- (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Six Nations, Wyandot, Shawnee, Delaware, and Ottawa Claims to Lands in Ohio"--Report, 30 Nov. 1953; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923- (Box Series IV-9)
  - "The Condemnation of Carnival in the Jesuit Relations"--Ms., 1982; Walsh, Martin W. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "From Cannibal to Clown: Observations on the Grotesque Mask Among the Woodland Indians"--Ms., [1985]; Walsh, Martin W. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "An Early History of the Dehorners, 1904-1910"--Ms., 1970; Weaver, Sally M. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "An Early History of the Movement for an Elective Form of Local Government among the Six Nations of Grand River, 1861-1903"--Ms., 1970; Weaver, Sally M. (Box Series IV-9)
  - "Politics of the Iroquois: An Analysis of Political Change"--Ms., 1973; 3 folders; Weaver, Sally M. (Box Series IV-10)
  - The Wampum Case--Ms., n.d.; Weaver, Sally M. (Box Series IV-10)
  - "Apios Rubber Project: Bibliography on Apios Tuberosa and Other Rubber Containing Legumes"--Report, 2 Apr. 1942; Whetzel, H.H. (Box Series IV-10)
  - "Cold Spring False Face Ceremonial: March 15, 1942"--Ms., White, Clayton C. (Box Series IV-10)
  - Re-elicitation, Grammatical Analysis, and Lexical Documentation of an Onondaga Text"--Ms., Woodbury, Hanni (Box Series IV-10)
  - "Land Surface and Lake Effects of Climate Changes on Agriculture in the Lower Great Lakes Region: Past, Present, and Future"--Ms., Wykoff, M. William (Box Series IV-10)
  - "Neutrals of the Southern Tier: Geology, Toponymy, and Protohistory"--Ms., Wykoff, M. William (Box Series IV-10)
- Series V. Research notes, 1912-1981; 17 boxes; 10.5 linear feet
  Loose notes, notebooks, and card files. The notes and notebooks are arranged by folder title and include the subjects of Seneca social and political organization, plants and medicine, song texts, and Seneca genealogies. Series V also includes six card files: "Ethnography of North America I," "Ethnography of North America II and Oceania + Australia," "Herbarium: Allegany Seneca Systematics," "Iroquois Medicines (F. Waugh Waugh)," "Sources and References in Lafitau / Political Anthropology," and "Materia Medica and Seneca Place Names." The card files provide a bibliography for those areas of study, as well as abstracts and quotations of source material. Notes which were too large to fit in the card file boxes were placed in folders and filed with the notes and notebooks. A photocopy of the first sheet of notes was placed in the card file with a cross reference. Similarly, photographs were removed to Series VI, and photocopies were placed in the card file with a cross reference.
  - Allegany Reservation, Quaker Bridge, New York: Field Notes--Notebook, Jul.-Sep. 1946 (Box Series V-1)
  - Allegheny VI: Henry, Sherman, Clara Redeye--Notebook, Summer 1934 (Box Series V-1)
  - Allegheny XI: Song Texts - Sherman Redeye, i'yo da't'a', oh gi we (from M. Turka)--Notebook, Summer 1934 (Box Series V-1)
  - Allegheny XV: John Jimerson, "The Little Water Society," Sex (p. 29), Invocation Text (p. 35)--Notebook, 24 Aug. 1934 (Box Series V-1)
  - Allegheny XVI: G[reat] Feather Dance, Green Corn Dance--Notebook, 27-30 Aug. 1934 (Box Series V-1)
  - American Anthropological Association Conference, 17-20 Nov. 1966 (Box Series V-2)
  - Bark Dishes, 1933-1934 (Box Series V-2)
  - Basketry, 1933-1938, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
    -See also Ser.VI, same title
  - Basketry, Cornhusk, 1912-1933, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
  - Basketry, Splint, 1938 (Box Series V-2)
  - Blackfeet, 1950 (Box Series V-2)
    -See also Ser.I, Cohen, Felix S.
    -See also Ser.I, Fickinger, Paul L.
    -See also Ser.I, U.S. Dept. of the Interior
  - Burden Strap, 1912, 1932-1933, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
  - Canfield, William Walker, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
    -See also Ser.I, Cookenham, Walt, Jr.
    -See also Ser.I, The Empire State Surveyor
    -See also Ser.I, Payne, Helen Canfield
  - "Car Book"--Notebook, 1947-1948 (Box Series V-2)
  - "Car Expense Book"--Notebook, [1934?] (Box Series V-2)
  - Charms. Hunting and Anti-Witchcraft, 1912-1915, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
  - Chautauqua (Box Series V-2)
    -See Ser.I, Carlson, Norman P.
  - Cherokee--From Clara and Sherman Redeye, 12 Aug. 1946 (Box Series V-2)
  - "The Cherokee and Seneca Peace"--From Seneca Jimmerson, 31 Aug. 1934 (Box Series V-2)
  - Cherokee Masks and the Eagle Dance--From Will West, 4-5 Dec. 1946 (Box Series V-2)
  - Clothing, Men's, 1912-1934, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
  - "Coldspring Mid-Winter F[estival]: Observations and Queries"--Notebook, 1939 (Box Series V-2)
  - Condolence Council, Ohgime. Cash Journal. II--Notebook, 1945 (Box Series V-2)
    -See also Ser.V, [Notebook] I, 1945
  - Corn Dance; Hand in Hand--From Jesse J. Cornplanter, 1948, 1949 (Box Series V-2)
  - "Cornplanter Seneca Reservation", 1942 (Box Series V-2)
  - Cradleboard, 1912-1933, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
  - Dances, 1933, 1941 (Box Series V-2)
  - Dekanawidah Legend--From Seth Newhouse, Apr. 1969 (Box Series V-2)
  - "Deskaheh on Cayuga Council", 1945 (Box Series V-2)
    -See also Ser.VI, [Deskaheh]
  - Divination, 1912-1915, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
  - Ethnography of North America I, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
  - Ethnography of North America II and Oceania + Australia, 1933, 1950, n.d. (Box Series V-2)
  - Feast of the Dead--From Howard Sky, 9 Nov. 1945 (Box Series V-3)
  - [Field Notebook], 1933 (Box Series V-3)
  - Field Notes--Notebook #1, Aug. 1933 (Box Series V-3)
  - "Field Notes"--Notebook #2, 1981 (Box Series V-3)
  - Field Notes II: Willy Titus, Genealogy, Aug. 1933 (Box Series V-3)
  - Field Notes III: F[alse] F[ace] Note (p. 36), J. C[rouse]'s Genealogy (p. 53)--Notebook, Aug. 1933 (Box Series V-3)
  - Firemaking, 1912-1913, 1933, n.d. (Box Series V-3)
  - Fishing, 1912, 1933, n.d. (Box Series V-3)
  - Food Utensils, 1912-1934, n.d. (Box Series V-3)
  - Games, 1912-1933, n.d. (Box Series V-3)
  - Genealogies, Seneca (Box Series V-3)
    - Folder #1, 1933-46 (Box Series V-3)
      Contains photocopies of Folders #2-4
    - Folders #2-3, 1933 (Box Series V-3)
      Originals
    - Folder #4, 1934-1946 (Box Series V-3)
      originals, folder title was "Census and Genealogies from Coldspring"
  - Handsome Lake, [197-?] (Box Series V-4)
  - Herbal Medicine, n.d. (Box Series V-4)
  - Herbarium: Allegany Seneca Systematics, n.d. (Box Series V-4)
  - "The History of Linking Arms Dance"--From James Crow, May 1935 (Box Series V-4)
  - Houses, 1912, 1934, n.d. (Box Series V-4)
  - Husk Dolls, 1938, n.d. (Box Series V-4)
  - Hyde Manuscript, 1960, 1964, n.d. (Box Series V-4)
  - "ICAES to Moscow"--Notebook, 1964 (Box Series V-4)
    Related Archival Materials note
    An audio diary of Fenton's travels in Russia is available. See Series VII: Recordings.
  - "The Indian Captivity Narrative" edited by Richard VanderBeets, 19 Jul. 1971 (Box Series V-4)
    -See also Ser.I, University of Tennessee Press
  - [Installation of Chief Peter Thomas at Six Nations Reserve], 1951 (Box Series V-4)
  - Iroquois, 1930s (Box Series V-4)
  - Iroquois Field Notes. Six Nations Reserve, Canada: Song Texts from the Six Nations on Grand River"--Notebook, 1945 (Box Series V-4)
    - "Iroquois Field Notes: Song Record Texts I"--Notebook #1, 1941 (Box Series V-4)
    - Iroquois Field Notes: Song [Record] Texts [II]--Notebook #2, 1941 (Box Series V-4)
    - Iroquois Field Notes: [Song Record Texts III]--Notebook #3, 1941 (Box Series V-4)
  - Iroquois Medicines, n.d. (Box Series V-5)
  - Iroquois Politics (Box Series V-5)
    - Folder #1, 1650-1699, [1980] (Box Series V-5)
    - Folder #2, Treaty References, 1700-1755, [1980] (Box Series V-5)
    - Folder #3, Treaty References, 1756-1783, n.d. (Box Series V-5)
    - Folder #4, 1784-1791, [1980] (Box Series V-5)
    - Folder #5, 1795-1842, [1980] (Box Series V-5)
  - Iroquois Towns, n.d. (Box Series V-5)
    -See also Ser.III, "Problems Arising From the Historic Northeastern Position of the Iroquois"--Ms.
  - [Iroquois Winter Festival at Six Nations Reservation, 10 Jan.-23 Feb. 1941] (Box Series V-5)
  - [Journal I], 1933 (Box Series V-5)
  - [Journal II], 1933 (Box Series V-5)
  - "Journal VIII"--Notebook, 1934 (Box Series V-5)
  - Klamath, 1950-1951 (Box Series V-5)
  - League, Meetings of the (1641-1774); Existence of (1634-1697), n.d. (Box Series V-5)
  - Materia Medica and Seneca Place Names (Box Series V-5)
  - Measurement, 1912-1913, n.d. (Box Series V-5)
  - "Medicinal Plants", n.d. (Box Series V-5)
  - "Medicinal Plants Arranged Systematically According to Botanical Names", n.d. (Box Series V-5)
  - "Medicine Notes from Journal", 1933-1934 (Box Series V-5)
  - Medicine - OKA, Automobile Mileage Book, Telephone Numbers, Addresses--Notebook, 1939 (Box Series V-5)
  - Migration Legend--From Peter Doctor, 31 Jul. 1935 (Box Series V-6)
  - Miscellaneous, [1937-1979] (Box Series V-6)
  - Moccasins, 1912-1934, n.d. (Box Series V-6)
  - Moses, A., 1935-1936 (Box Series V-6)
  - Music, n.d. (Box Series V-6)
  - Musical Instruments, 1933-1934, n.d. (Box Series V-6)
  - Newhouse (Seth) Ms., 1969 (Box Series V-6)
  - [Notebook] I, 1945 (Box Series V-6)
    -See also Ser.V, Condolence Council, Ohgime. Cash Journal II--Notebook
  - Olbrechts, Frans M.--Notes on his Writings, n.d. (Box Series V-6)
  - Pack Frame, 1912, 1938 (Box Series V-6)
  - "Passenger Pigeon Hunts among Cornplanter Seneca", 1942 (Box Series V-6)
  - "Petty Cash Journal"--Notebook, Summer 1934 (Box Series V-6)
  - Photograph Records, 1933 (Box Series V-6)
  - "Plants"--Notebook, 1938 (Box Series V-6)
  - "Plants. Field Notes I"--Notebook #1, 1939 (Box Series V-6)
  - "Plants. Field Notes I"--Notebook #2, 1940 (Box Series V-6)
  - "Prediction of 'De-Ka-Na-Wi-Dah.' Of the North American Empire [Confederacy]: (The Way It Shall Fall, (And Be Revived) to be Destroyed"--From Seth Newhouse, Apr. 1969 (Box Series V-7)
  - "Record 23A", 1947 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca--From Lyman Johnson, 1933, 1935 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca IV--Notebook, 1933 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca V--Notebook, 1933 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca Field Notes I--Notebook, 1934 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca Field Notes II--Notebook, 1934 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca Field Notes III--Notebook, 1934 (Box Series V-7)
  - [Seneca Field Notes IV]--Notebook, 1934 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca [Field Notes] V--Notebook, 1934 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca Field Notes XII: Allegheny--Notebook, Summer 1934 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca Field Notes XIII: Allegheny--Notebook, Aug. 1934 (Box Series V-7)
  - Seneca Indians at Coldspring on the Allegheny Reservation. Journal of Field Expedition to the, Jun.-Sep. 1933; 3 folders (Box Series V-8)
  - Seneca Reburial Ceremony, n.d. (Box Series V-8)
  - Seneca Social Dances (Texts and Notes by W.C. Sturtevant and Solon Jones)--Contents List of Recording, 1957 (Box Series V-8)
  - Silversmithing, 1912, 1914 (Box Series V-8)
  - Six Nations Ceremonies--From Simeon Gibson, Summer 1940; 2 folders (Box Series V-8)
  - Six Nations Material in Dartmouth College Archives, Oct. 1968 (Box Series V-8)
    -See also Ser.I, Dartmouth College Library
  - Six Nations, Ohsweken, Canada. Field Trip--Notebook, 1969 (Box Series V-8)
  - Six Nations Res[erve]--Notebook, Sept.-Oct. 1943 (Box Series V-8)
  - Six Nations Reserve, Brantford, Apr.-Jun. 1969 (Box Series V-8)
  - Six Nations Reserve Spring Trip: Cash Journal, Recorded Ohgime--Notebook, 1945 (Box Series V-8)
  - Social Dances, 1933-1942, n.d. (Box Series V-8)
  - "Song Texts IV. Six Nations Reserve, Canada"--Notebook, Oct.-Nov. 1945 (Box Series V-8)
  - Sources and References in Lafitau / Political Anthropology (Box Series V-8)
  - "Tádogat and His Adventures among the Choctaw"--From John Jimmerson, 17 Aug. 1934 (Box Series V-9)
  - Taos, 1948-1950 (Box Series V-9)
  - Time Measurement, 1912-1915 (Box Series V-9)
  - Tonawanda I. Social Organization, Museum Coll[ection]s Buffalo--Notebook, Jun. 1934 (Box Series V-9)
  - Tonawanda II: Waugh Queries - 1912, Medicine--Notebook, Jun. 1934 (Box Series V-9)
  - "Tonawanda III: Kinship Terms"--Notebook, Jun. 1934 (Box Series V-9)
  - "Tonawanda IV", [193-] (Box Series V-9)
  - Tonawanda IV: Mostly Med[icine] Soc[ieties], Waugh Queries II, E. David--Notebook, Jun. 1934 (Box Series V-9)
  - Tonawanda V, Apr. 1935 (Box Series V-9)
  - Tonawanda IX: Chiefs HRE [Henry Redeye], Houses, Chief Tä wan ya's (Wolf Clan), Da'ho (Boy's Name)--Notebook, 3 Aug. 1934 (Box Series V-9)
  - Tonawanda: Da ga'non gi [To Everett Parker (Hawk Clan)] ho ya'dos'hä' (His Book)--Notebook, 1934 (Box Series V-9)
  - Tonawanda Reservation I--Notebook, Feb. 1935 (Box Series V-9)
  - Tonawanda Reservation II: Political Organization, Peter Doctor (Turtle)--Notebook, 1935 (Box Series V-9)
  - Tonawanda Reservation III: Field Notes--Notebook, 1935 (Box Series V-9)
  - Transportation, 1912, 1935, n.d. (Box Series V-10)
    -See also Ser.I, Davidson, D. Sutherland
    -See also Ser.VI, Snowshoes of Amos Snow's Grandfather
  - Traps, 1912-1938, n.d. (Box Series V-10)
    -See also Ser.I, Cooper, John M.
    -See also Ser.I, Deardorff, Merle H., 5 Apr. 1944
  - Turtle's War Party--From Peter Doctor, 31 Jul. 1935 (Box Series V-10)
  - United States Indian Service--Notebook, Aug. 1936 (Box Series V-10)
  - Wampum (Box Series V-10)
    - Folder #1, 1600-1700, [1980] (Box Series V-10)
    - Folder #2, 1700-1788, [1980] (Box Series V-10)
    - Folder #3, 1789-1800, [1980] (Box Series V-10)
  - Weapons, 1912-1944, n.d. (Box Series V-10)
  - Witchcraft, 1912-1915 (Box Series V-10)
  - Ethnography of North America I, n.d. (Box Series V-11)
  - Ethnography of North America II and Oceania + Australia (Box Series V-12)
  - Herbarium: Allegany Seneca Systematics, n.d. (Box Series V-13)
    "Herbarium" cont'd in "Seneca Place Names"
  - Iroquois Material Culture, 1969 (Box Series V-14)
    -See also Ser.IV, Cook, Garrett, "A Proposed Catalogue for Iroquois Material Culture: Some Ramifications"
  - Iroquois Medicines (F. Waugh Waugh), n.d. (Box Series V-15)
  - Sources and References in Lafitau / Political Anthropology (Box Series V-16)
  - Materia Medica (Allegany Seneca, Caughnawaga); Seneca Place Names and Related Activities (Box Series V-17)
    Continues "Herbarium"
- Series VI. Photographs, 1880-1993; 12 boxes; 7 linear feet
  Photographs, both positive and negative, of Fenton's activities while in the field, artifacts, and false faces, and friends. The majority of the negatives in this series document Fenton's field work in the 1930s and 1940s. Fenton assigned a number to each negative and maintained an index which is arranged by negative number; this index is filed in Series VI under "Negatives." There are few prints of Fenton's field work, with the exception of his friends and informants, including Simeon Gibson, Helen Harris, Henry Redeye, Howard Sky, and Jones Snow. Photographs of false faces account for most of the prints. The false face material falls into two sections according to its original order. The first section, filed under "False Faces," retains Fenton's original distinctions by type of false face (e.g. "smiling," "spoon mouth blower"). Additional false face photographs removed from Series I-V have been titled "False Faces" but have not been interfiled with Fenton's original files. The other false face photographs were originally filed with the drafts of The False Faces of the Iroquois. This section includes information on printing, reduction or enlargement, captions, and figures; these prints have been filed under The False Faces of the Iroquois. Series VI also includes several photographs of the wampum transfer from the Museum of the American Indian to the Six Nations Reserve in 1988. For additional prints of several of Fenton's negatives, see the George S. Snyderman Papers, Coll. No. 51.
  Native American Images Note: Over 1,000 negatives of Iroquoian life on the Tonawanda and Allegany reservations of western New York from 1933-1951. Images depict Seneca Indians social customs including dances, sports, festivals, societies and other everyday activities. Taken by Fenton with Native American consultants Chauncey Johnny John, Jonas Snow, and Henry Redeye, the 1937-1941 negatives show details of wearing and carving of false faces. Also, over 1,500 black and white, some color, photographs of museum exhibited false faces. Collected from the Museum of the American Indian-Heye Foundation, The Royal Ontario Museum of Archaeology, and the Buffalo Historical Society, the black and red wooden masks illustrate such expressions as hanging mouth, protruding tongue, and grimace with teeth. The balance of the collection contain photographs of wampum, corn husk masks, rattles, and drums with some oversize maps of Native American reservations near Lakes Erie and Ontario. Note: Iroquoian False Faces are considered sacred so respectful use of the collection is requested.
  - Allegany and Cornplanter Indian negatives by Dorothy Skinner--List (Box Series VI-1)
    -See Ser.IIa, same title
  - Allegany School of Natural History, 1938 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Black, Barber (Box Series VI-1)
    -See Ser.VI, Musical Instruments
  - Bowl, [1983] (Box Series VI-1)
  - Bowl, n.d. (Box Series VI-1)
  - [Canadian Conference on Indian Welfare] (Box Series VI-1)
  - Cayuga nomination strings, n.d. (Box Series VI-1)
  - Conklin, Harold C. in High Sierras, [1 Jul. 1944] (Box Series VI-1)
  - Cornplanter, Jesse J., Dec. 1928 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Cornplanter, Jesse J., 1934 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Cornplanter, Jesse J., 1938, n.d. (Box Series VI-1)
  - Cornplanter, Jesse J., Jan. 1939 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Cornplanter, Jesse J., 1947 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Cornplanter, Jesse J.--Slides, 1952 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Cornplanter, Jesse J.--Drawings, n.d. (Box Series VI-1)
  - Creeks, Aug. 1938 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Crow, Ernie, 1966 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Deerfield, Indian attack at, 29 Feb. 1704, [1968] (Box Series VI-1)
  - [Diorama of maskers by Isabell Skye], 1984 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Drum beater sticks (Grand Rapids), [1983] (Box Series VI-1)
  - Eakins Oval, n.d. (Box Series VI-1)
  - Einhorn, Arthur--False face painting, [1981] (Box Series VI-1)
  - False face (Mitchell Indian Museum)--Slide, [1985] (Box Series VI-1)
  - False face (Six Nations Reserve, Caledonia), [1988] (Box Series VI-1)
  - False faces (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #1, 1905-1941 (Box Series VI-1)
      smiling
    - Folder #2, 1940 (Box Series VI-1)
      grimace with teeth
    - Folder #3, 1908-1940 (Box Series VI-1)
      crooked or twisted up
    - Folder #4, 1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      crooked or twisted down
    - Folder #5, 1912-1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      hanging mouth
    - Folder #6, 1918, 1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      whistling
    - Folder #7, 1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      oval distended
    - Folder #8, 1918, 1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      protruding tongue
    - Folder #9, 1912, 1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      square mouth blower
    - Folder #10, 1908-1964 (Box Series VI-2)
      bi-funnelate blower
    - Folder #11, 1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      spoon mouth blower
    - Folder #12, 1908-1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      modified distended var. spoon mouth
    - Folder #13, 1908-1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      straight distended
    - Folder #14, 1938-1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      horned
    - Folder #15, 1918 (Box Series VI-2)
      animal
    - Folder #16, 1916 (Box Series VI-2)
      wind gods & U.S. National Museum
    - Folder #17, 1916-1940, 1967 (Box Series VI-2)
      husk faces or bushy heads
    - Folder #18, 1940 (Box Series VI-2)
      mask models
    - Folder #19, 1953, 1962 (Box Series VI-2)
  - False faces (Brown University), [1989] (Box Series VI-2)
  - False faces (Conable, Barber B., Jr.), 1989-1993 (Box Series VI-2)
  - False faces (Holt, Philip J.), n.d. (Box Series VI-2)
  - False faces (Isaacs, Avrom), 1993 (Box Series VI-2)
  - False faces (Sotheby's), 1993 (Box Series VI-2)
  - False Faces of the Iroquois (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #1, 1937-1953 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #2a, 1980-1984 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #2b, 1980-1984 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #3, 1984 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #4, 1984 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #5, 1984 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #6, [1987] (Box Series VI-3)
      plates 1-1 to 2-23
    - Folder #7, [1987] (Box Series VI-3)
      plates 5-1 to 8-25
    - Folder #8, [1987] (Box Series VI-4)
      plates 9-1 to 11-16
    - Folder #9, [1987] (Box Series VI-4)
      plates 12-1 to 18-1
    - Folder #10, [1987] (Box Series VI-4)
      alternate photos.